<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>security on Particl Project Wiki</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tags/security/</link><description>Recent content in security on Particl Project Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://particl.wiki/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Securely storing Recovery Phrases</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/security/recovery-phrase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/security/recovery-phrase/</guid><description>Recovery Phrases (sometimes also called Mnemonic or just Seed) are strings of usually 12, 18 or 24 words, which are used to recover crypto wallets in cases of emergency. That being said, whoever gets access to your Recovery Phrase can access your coins as well. This presents a security risk if your Recovery Phrase gets stolen or discovered by some malicious actor.
Finding the right balance Each security layer used to protect your Recovery Phrase (and optionally Recovery Passphrase) makes it harder for everyone to get access to your coins – that includes both attackers and yourself.</description></item><item><title>Backup &amp; Restore wallet</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/security/backup-restore-wallet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/security/backup-restore-wallet/</guid><description>Your funds are backed up by Recovery Phrase (~ mnemonic seed) during wallet creation and that is enough to keep your coins safe. However if you want to backup all the additional data like addresses saved in Address Book and more, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to backup your wallet.dat file.
Always backup your wallet.dat to a secure place (USB, external drive etc.) – if anyone would get access to it and knew your wallet password, they could steal your coins!</description></item><item><title>How to choose a good password</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/security/good-passwords/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/security/good-passwords/</guid><description>Trezor wrote a very detailed and in-depth article about choosing strong passphrases for protecting recovery seeds. You can obviously follow this guide to password/passphrase-protect any kind of valuable information (like your Particl recovery seed).</description></item><item><title>Verify integrity of downloads</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/security/verify-downloads/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/security/verify-downloads/</guid><description>About checksums While compiling from source is the recommended and most secure way to build the Particl platform, the team realizes this is an advanced technique that a large number of users aren&amp;rsquo;t comfortable with. For most users, each release is distributed with source code and pre-compiled distributions for Windows, Mac &amp;amp; Linux.
For Particl Core, the latest release can be found here: https://github.com/particl/particl-core/releases/latest
For Particl Desktop, the latest release can be found here: https://github.</description></item></channel></rss>