<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Help &amp; Support on Particl Project Wiki</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/support/</link><description>Recent content in Help &amp; Support on Particl Project Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://beta.particl.wiki/support/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fixing syncing issues</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/support/syncing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/support/syncing/</guid><description>Particl wallets are a network-based software. Make sure that no firewall or anti-virus software is blocking Particl from running or connecting the internet. If in doubt, disable them for testing purposes and enable them afterwards if you have identified your problem.
Update to latest version Make sure you&amp;rsquo;re running on latest version.
If not, update your wallet.
Reindex blockchain Relaunch the client with -reindex flag:
Windows Windows Particl Desktop: FIXME Particl Core: FIXME macOS macOS Particl Desktop: launch via /particl-desktop.</description></item><item><title>Connections &amp; peers</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/support/connections/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/support/connections/</guid><description>Clear banned peers Opening Console in Particl Desktop Open Console:
Particl Desktop: click on the terminal/console icon in bottom left corner Particl Core: Help → Debug window → Console tab Enter clearbanned, press Enter and restart wallet.
Find peers from scratch Delete your peers.dat file in Particl directory. This will force the app to find new connections to peers.
Time offset error If you see a time offset error icon, it means that your machine is either ahead of behind a few seconds compared to your peers.</description></item><item><title>Chain forks</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/support/fork/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/support/fork/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re experiencing that Particl Desktop or Particl Core wallet is not syncing any further, then it might be because you got caught on a fork due to the latest hardfork.
If you execute any transaction during this time, it will appear as if you&amp;rsquo;ve lost the coins, but don&amp;rsquo;t worry. Nothing has left your wallet.
Getting on the right chain Getting your client back to a working state requires a bit of work.</description></item></channel></rss>