<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>staking on Particl Project Wiki</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/tags/staking/</link><description>Recent content in staking on Particl Project Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://beta.particl.wiki/tags/staking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Specifications</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/blockchain/particl-specifications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/blockchain/particl-specifications/</guid><description>Blockchain Codebase Always up-to-date with latest Bitcoin Core Consensus mechanism Particl Proof-of-Stake (PPoS) Block time 120 seconds (5× faster than BTC) Block size 2 MB (2× larger than BTC) Coin supply Total &amp;amp; circulating supply 9+ million PART (check link for exact number) Community fund ~33,000 PART (owned by PART community) Staking Block reward ~0.</description></item><item><title>Hosting your own Coldstaking Pool</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/advanced/hosting-coldstaking-pool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/advanced/hosting-coldstaking-pool/</guid><description>For information about hosting your own coldstaking pool, visit the documentation in the particl/coldstakepool repository on GitHub:
VPS Setup Example</description></item><item><title>How to stake</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/overview/</guid><description>Staking methods Comparison Standalone staking Cold staking To learn more in-depth about Particl&amp;rsquo;s Staking feature, read Particl Staking (intro).
Staking methods You can choose from few options on how to stake:
Standalone – staking happens directly in your desktop wallet, your PC should be online ideally 24/7 (see below) Staking on a Pool – easily &amp;ldquo;pair&amp;rdquo; your desktop wallet with a Staking Pool; staking will happen automatically on pool Staking on dedicated staking device (DSD) – a fancy way to describe staking on your own SBC like Raspberry Pi or Rock64 without need to rely on third-party pool Comparison Standalone Staking pools Dedicated staking devices Difficulty to setup easiest easy moderate Staking happens directly in wallet on a pool on dedicated device Staking type &amp;ldquo;hot&amp;rdquo; staking Cold Staking Cold Staking Fees – 1–3 % – Security lower high high Howto guides – setup guide setup guide Standalone staking is easiest and fastest way to start staking.</description></item><item><title>Cold staking setup</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/cold-staking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/cold-staking/</guid><description>Before we dive into this guide, you might want to familiarize yourself with theory of cold staking, so that you know what we&amp;rsquo;re doing and why.
Particl&amp;rsquo;s cold staking setup is quite flexible, meaning there are many options how to stake – each approach has its pros and cons. This guide will outline all the possible variants, so that you can choose your own balance between convenience, privacy and security.</description></item><item><title>About Particl's PoS</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/staking/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/staking/intro/</guid><description>About Particl Staking Passive Income Cold Staking Cold Hardware Staking Quantum-resistance &amp;amp; Privacy About Particl Staking Proof-of-Stake (PoS) is a type of algorithm by which a cryptocurrency blockchain network aims to achieve distributed consensus. In PoS-based cryptocurrencies, the creator of the next block is chosen via various combinations of random selection of wealth and age. In contrast, the algorithm of Proof-of-Work (PoW) based cryptocurrencies such as bitcoin rewards participants who solve complicated cryptographical puzzles in order to validate transactions and create new blocks (i.</description></item><item><title>Cold Staking Pools</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/staking/pools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/staking/pools/</guid><description>The importance of decentralization Available Staking Pools Advanced Running your own Pool In the context of cryptocurrency mining, a mining pool is the pooling of resources by miners, who share their processing power over a network, to split the reward equally, according to the amount of work they contributed to the probability of finding a block. — Wikipedia</description></item><item><title>Dedicated Staking Devices</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/staking/dedicated-devices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/staking/dedicated-devices/</guid><description> This article hasn't been written yet, we're working on it! Want to help out? Contribute your articles!</description></item><item><title>Partyman staking utility</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/staking/partyman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/staking/partyman/</guid><description>About Partyman Use cases Advantages Features About Partyman Partyman displaying staking status Partyman automates all kinds of heavy lifting related to running your own (staking) node. It&amp;rsquo;s very lightweight and runs on many platforms, including ARM (for DSD like Raspberry Pi, Rock64 and others).
As CLI, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t offer any graphical interface, but it&amp;rsquo;s still very usable and user-friendly.</description></item><item><title>Staking on DSD with Partyman</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/on-dedicated-device/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/on-dedicated-device/</guid><description>A Staking Node is a full blockchain node which has been configured to stake on behalf of your wallet (aka it has been delegated staking power over your wallet). The Staking Node is a computer running Particl that is always on and always connected to the internet. A Raspberry Pi 3 or comparable device (DSD) makes a perfect staking node as it consumes very little energy, is compact and easy to tailor for dedicated tasks.</description></item><item><title>Cold staking on Ledger wallet</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/ledger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/ledger/</guid><description>This tutorial assumes Particl has been properly installed on your Ledger Nano S/X hardware device and that your Particl Core wallet is set up for Particl on Ledger.
Requirements Before starting the setup process, make sure you have:
Cold staking public key – you can get it by either: self-hosting a cold staking node (on Raspberri Pi/Rock64 etc.) or by joining one of the available staking pools A Ledger hardware wallet with Particl installed on it Ledger Live app ready to use Particl Core wallet installed and fully synced Staking setup Get your staking public key Staking Pool Via staking pool Choose one of the available staking pools and note somewhere its staking public key (they are usually right there on the top of the page).</description></item></channel></rss>