<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Particl Wiki on Particl Project Wiki</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/</link><description>Recent content in Particl Wiki on Particl Project Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://geekdocs.de/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Latest Bitcoin codebase</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/blockchain/bitcoin-codebase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/blockchain/bitcoin-codebase/</guid><description>PART is hosted by its own blockchain and is not a token built on another chain (i.e. ERC-20 tokens).
Advantages Being built on the latest Bitcoin codebase not only allows the Particl platform to benefit from both Bitcoin’s stability and security, but also enables developers to leverage and easily fork any product, service and technology development from the Bitcoin developer community.
Recent Bitcoin developments implemented in Particl include but are not limited to:</description></item><item><title>Scalability</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/blockchain/blockchain-scalability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/blockchain/blockchain-scalability/</guid><description>Native Segregated Witness (Segwit) Bulletproofs Lightning Network Instant Payments Scalability Low Cost Cross-Chain Data Storage Network (DSN) Native Segregated Witness (Segwit) The Particl platform is the first blockchain in the industry to ever be deployed with a native implementation of Segwit.
This has the added benefit of making all transactions (including private ones) go through Segwit by default, resulting in better scalability and cheaper transaction fees.</description></item><item><title>Specifications</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/blockchain/particl-specifications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/blockchain/particl-specifications/</guid><description>Blockchain Codebase Always up-to-date with latest Bitcoin Core Consensus mechanism Particl Proof-of-Stake (PPoS) Block time 120 seconds (5× faster than BTC) Block size 2 MB (2× larger than BTC) Coin supply Total &amp;amp; circulating supply 9+ million PART (check link for exact number) Community fund ~33,000 PART (owned by PART community) Staking Block reward ~0.</description></item><item><title>Transaction types</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/privacy/transaction-types/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/privacy/transaction-types/</guid><description>As the highest privacy state requires the most transaction fee, it may not always be the best type of transaction depending on the situation, especially when privacy is not predominantly required by the user.
Particl&amp;#39;s multiple privacy states Public Blind Anon Staking Privacy ∗ ∗∗ ∗∗∗ Hidden TX amount Anon TX participants TX fees $ $$ $$$ Open Marketplace Public Blind Anon Paying for Listing fees – – Flagging items – – Purchasing items – – Funding MAD Escrow – – Why has PART different privacy states?</description></item><item><title>Getting started</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/getting-started/</guid><description>This series of guides will walk you through the first steps into Particl ecosystem. Buckle up!
Learn about Particl This Wiki is a great informational and supportive resource for all things Particl. Understanding the whole project might be a bit overwhelming, so we propose studing it piece by piece. Many topics are covered here, but at the bare minimum, you should read all the articles marked with ★ symbol as those are the most important ones:</description></item><item><title>Particl Desktop</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/wallets/particl-desktop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/wallets/particl-desktop/</guid><description>About Particl Desktop Features Installation Creating a new wallet Staking Recommended for beginners and majority of users Preview of Particl Desktop 3.0 About Particl Desktop While it does not currently contain all advanced features (like Particl Core), Particl Desktop is a recommended wallet for majority of users.
This wallet is intended to be the centerpiece and default wallet of the Particl platform and is heavily under development.</description></item><item><title>Particl Open Marketplace</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/overview/</guid><description>About Open Marketplace Features Payments Listings No metadata IP address anonymization About Open Marketplace Buy and sell products and services from anyone else in the world without leaving a trail and using your favorite cryptocurrency.
The Particl Open Marketplace is a hybrid between blockchain and peer-to-peer technologies. It operates with no central authority or middleman and is exclusively owned and operated by its network of participants.</description></item><item><title>Particl with Tor</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/privacy/tor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/privacy/tor/</guid><description>a) Using the Tor Browser b) Using the Tor Daemon c) Tor as a Hidden Service The only privacy protocol that’s not enabled by default on Particl Desktop is the ability to hide your IP address using the Tor network.
While it could eventually be enabled by default or through the Settings page, Tor currently needs to be activated manually to route your Particl Desktop connection through its network.</description></item><item><title>Proposals</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/misc/proposals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/misc/proposals/</guid><description> This article hasn't been written yet, we're working on it!</description></item><item><title>Running multiple wallets</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/privacy/multiwallet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/privacy/multiwallet/</guid><description>Multiwallet setup Particl Desktop Particl Core Autostart multiwallet Particl Desktop Particl Core Linux You might want to create and use multiple wallets for different usage. The goal is to separate your finances, so they won&amp;rsquo;t mix up. This approach will also help you gain a bit more privacy (never linking all of your available funds).</description></item><item><title>Wallets overview</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/wallets/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/wallets/overview/</guid><description>You can use one or all of them, it&amp;rsquo;s up to you.
Overview Particl Desktop is a recommended wallet for most users as it offers the best of Particl&amp;rsquo;s features, including Particl Open Marketplace. Desktop Main, desktop wallets for Windows, macOS and Linux
Particl Desktop – Main, feature-rich wallet for Particl with all bells and whistles Particl Core – Qt-based wallet focused on stability and advanced features Particl Copay – Mobile &amp;amp; desktop wallet with multi-sig for increased security Hardware Compatible hardware wallets for usage with Particl Core</description></item><item><title>Backup &amp; Restore wallet</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/security/backup-restore-wallet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/security/backup-restore-wallet/</guid><description>Your funds are backed up by Recovery Phrase (~ mnemonic seed) during wallet creation and that is enough to keep your coins safe. However if you want to backup all the additional data like addresses saved in Address Book and more, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to backup your wallet.dat file.
Always backup your wallet.dat to a secure place (USB, external drive etc.) – if anyone would get access to it and knew your wallet password, they could steal your coins!</description></item><item><title>MAD Escrow</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/mad-escrow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/mad-escrow/</guid><description>About MAD Escrow Game Theory How does it work? Private by design Scalability About MAD Escrow Marketplaces usually have mechanisms in place to resolve disputes between buyers and vendors. This is a vital part of e-commerce because trusting strangers, especially when money is involved, has never proven to be reliable. As buyers and vendors do not know and trust each other, there has to be protection against one of the party never honoring their end of the trade.</description></item><item><title>Particl Core</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/wallets/particl-core/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/wallets/particl-core/</guid><description>Preview of Particl Core Particl Core is more lightweight than Particl Desktop, offers some advanced features like Coin Control and compatibility with hardware wallets.
However it acts like a wallet only, so you won&amp;rsquo;t have access to Particl Open Marketplace.
Download Particl Core Report bugs Features Browse &amp;amp; compare Particl Core&amp;rsquo;s features with other available wallets.
Getting started Installation Please note that even though some of these steps are optional/recommended, it is highly advised to follow all of them as it secures your funds from being lost.</description></item><item><title>Particl Foundation</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/misc/particl-foundation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/misc/particl-foundation/</guid><description>About Particl Foundation Purpose Funding &amp;amp; finances Initial funding Financial reports Donations Board members Address About Particl Foundation The Particl Foundation (Particl Stiftung) is a non-profit Swiss foundation registered in Zug on July 2017 with the help of Swiss law firm MME enabling the organization and deployment of funding and logistics to ensure the safe development of the Particl project and vision.</description></item><item><title>About Particl's PoS</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/staking/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/staking/intro/</guid><description>About Particl Staking Passive Income Cold Staking Cold Hardware Staking Quantum-resistance &amp;amp; Privacy About Particl Staking Proof-of-Stake (PoS) is a type of algorithm by which a cryptocurrency blockchain network aims to achieve distributed consensus. In PoS-based cryptocurrencies, the creator of the next block is chosen via various combinations of random selection of wealth and age. In contrast, the algorithm of Proof-of-Work (PoW) based cryptocurrencies such as bitcoin rewards participants who solve complicated cryptographical puzzles in order to validate transactions and create new blocks (i.</description></item><item><title>Cold Staking Pools</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/staking/pools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/staking/pools/</guid><description>The importance of decentralization Available Staking Pools Advanced Running your own Pool In the context of cryptocurrency mining, a mining pool is the pooling of resources by miners, who share their processing power over a network, to split the reward equally, according to the amount of work they contributed to the probability of finding a block. — Wikipedia</description></item><item><title>Dedicated Staking Devices</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/staking/dedicated-devices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/staking/dedicated-devices/</guid><description> This article hasn't been written yet, we're working on it!</description></item><item><title>Ledger Wallet</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/wallets/ledger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/wallets/ledger/</guid><description>Ledger Nano S About Ledger Wallet Requirements Installation Ledger Particl app Particl Core configuration Usage Sending PART using Ledger Cold staking on Ledger About Ledger Wallet Ledger Nano (S/X) is a hardware wallet which stores user&amp;rsquo;s private keys in a secure hardware device.
Hardware wallets have major advantages over standard software wallets: private keys are stored in a secure chip, and cannot be transferred out of the device.</description></item><item><title>Marketplace fees</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/fees/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/fees/</guid><description>Traditional marketplaces usually have pretty complicated or extensive fee schedules. Depending on various variables such as what kind of products you sell, the number of transactions you do, your membership subscription plan, your feedback, and similar sets of data, fees can vary greatly.
The total cost associated with selling online usually includes a listing fee, a final value fee (sales fee taken on the value of the item), a subscription fee, a payment processing fee, escrow fee, and more.</description></item><item><title>Orders</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/orders/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/orders/</guid><description> This article hasn't been written yet, we're working on it!</description></item><item><title>Particl as Tor Hidden Service</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/privacy/tor-hidden-service/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/privacy/tor-hidden-service/</guid><description>Download Particl wallet Install Tor Define HS in Tor config Find your IP for HS Modify particl.conf Start wallet It also protects your machine from geolocation and its possible ugly consequences, and automatically sets you up for both incoming and outgoing connections, helping the Particl network. It is recommended to always run the Particl through Tor.
This guide is written purely for Linux (specificaly Ubuntu-based distributions).</description></item><item><title>Partyman staking utility</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/staking/partyman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/staking/partyman/</guid><description>About Partyman Use cases Advantages Features About Partyman Partyman displaying staking status Partyman automates all kinds of heavy lifting related to running your own (staking) node. It&amp;rsquo;s very lightweight and runs on many platforms, including ARM (for DSD like Raspberry Pi, Rock64 and others).
As CLI, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t offer any graphical interface, but it&amp;rsquo;s still very usable and user-friendly.</description></item><item><title>Tips for increasing privacy</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/privacy/tips/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/privacy/tips/</guid><description>Basics Particl Transactions Balances Network Other resources Here are a few tips to keep you private as much as possible:
Basics Never brag about how much PART or BTC you own, online or offline. All it does is bringing attention to you; scammers and hackers would surely love to get a piece of your pie. It&amp;rsquo;s not worth the risk.</description></item><item><title>Coin Control</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/privacy/coin-control/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/privacy/coin-control/</guid><description> This article hasn't been written yet, we're working on it!</description></item><item><title>Community governance</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/governance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/governance/</guid><description>It is instead governed by its community of holders rather than a team of staff or a third-parties.
Decentralized moderation Since it is fully anonymous, it is not unlikely that undesirable items and services would be listed for sale. This is why there has to be a way to moderate the marketplace. This ensures the marketplace preserves its legitimacy and that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t become an enabler of immoral businesses and activities.</description></item><item><title>Trezor Wallet</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/wallets/trezor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/wallets/trezor/</guid><description> This article hasn't been written yet, we're working on it!</description></item><item><title>Particl Copay</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/wallets/particl-copay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/wallets/particl-copay/</guid><description>About Particl Copay While it doesn&amp;rsquo;t offer all of available features (compared to other Particl wallets) it offers some unique ones.
Mainly, Particl Copay is the most accessible mobile Particl wallet and allows user-friendly multisignature wallets for increased security of your funds, or even sharing the wallet across multiple people.
Google Play App Store Download for desktop Report bugs Preview of Particl Copay app on mobile Features Browse &amp;amp; compare Particl Copay&amp;rsquo;s features with other available wallets.</description></item><item><title>Private markets</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/private-bubbles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/private-bubbles/</guid><description>They are not accessible from the public interface of the Open Marketplace. The only way to access them is by entering their unique Market ID in the Particl Desktop client.
The Market ID is only known to the person that initially generated the private market and to the people he shared it with. While private markets aren&amp;rsquo;t part of the first mainnet version of the Open Marketplace, they will be implemented during the Beta phase of development.</description></item><item><title>Currency agnosticism</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/currency-agnosticism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/currency-agnosticism/</guid><description>What&amp;rsquo;s currency agnosticism? Atomic Swaps Third-Party Integrations What&amp;rsquo;s currency agnosticism? That means buyers aren&amp;rsquo;t limited to using the PART coin as a form of payment. They are able to use many currencies, including Bitcoin, among others. This provides a use-case for many different coins and gives them a fee-less and untraceable way to spend their cryptocurrencies without having to either go through a third-party or sell their coins for fiat on exchanges.</description></item><item><title>Particl CLI</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/wallets/particl-cli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/wallets/particl-cli/</guid><description>About Particl CLI Features Getting started Installation Backup &amp;amp; Restore Usage Basic commands Informative Actions Confidential Transactions (Blind) Wallet unlocking With enhanced privacy Standard unlocking Preview of Particl CLI About Particl CLI Particl-cli offers all the essential features, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t include all the advanced bells and whistles of Particl graphical clients.</description></item><item><title>Data Storage Network (DSN)</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/data-storage-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/data-storage-network/</guid><description>Contrary to on-chain storage, storing data on DSN allows the platform to scale well regardless of the amount of data it uses. This form of storage works without relying on servers and without centralizing powers into masternodes.
About DSN DSN is a generic term that describes a specific set of software with the purpose of storing and retrieving data on the internet. The usage of the term DSN is simply a layer of abstraction.</description></item><item><title>Secure Messaging (SMSG)</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/smsg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/smsg/</guid><description>About SMSG SMSG is a decentralized P2P message mixnet where all nodes store a copy of everyone&amp;rsquo;s end-to-end encrypted messages and data for a duration of 48 hours (which can be increased for a fee).
It is the default and most private DSN available for use on the platform.
The reference implementation is developed in C++ and incorporated into the Particl daemon. It operates parallel to Particl&amp;rsquo;s network and is hosted on the same nodes running the blockchain.</description></item><item><title>Hardware wallets</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/wallets/hardware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/wallets/hardware/</guid><description>Advantages They have major advantages over standard software wallets: private keys are stored in a protected area of a microcontroller, and cannot be transferred out of the device in plaintext. That means your funds are safe even when connected to an infected or malicious computer or a phishing/scam web page.
Supported hardware wallets Ledger wallet Particl is currently supported by Ledger Wallet and has been integrated in such a way that it supports cold staking.</description></item><item><title>Open Market Protocol (OMP)</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/open-market-protocol/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/open-market-protocol/</guid><description>Design Extensibility Privacy Portability It is a standardized and open format containing most of the economic interactions of an online marketplace. The OMP is available as an open-source protocol on Particl&amp;rsquo;s Github page and is licensed under the terms of the MIT license.
Read Open Market Protocol documentation for in-depth info. Design The Open Market Protocol is divided into two distinct formats.</description></item></channel></rss>