<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Particl Wiki on Particl Project Wiki</title><link>https://particl.wiki/</link><description>Recent content in Particl Wiki on Particl Project Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://particl.wiki/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Latest Bitcoin codebase</title><link>https://particl.wiki/learn/blockchain/bitcoin-codebase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/learn/blockchain/bitcoin-codebase/</guid><description>PART is hosted by its own blockchain and is not a token built on another chain (i.e. ERC-20 tokens).
Advantages Being built on the latest Bitcoin codebase not only allows the Particl platform to benefit from both Bitcoin’s stability and security, but also enables developers to leverage and easily fork any product, service and technology development from the Bitcoin developer community.
Recent Bitcoin developments implemented in Particl include but are not limited to:</description></item><item><title>Scalability</title><link>https://particl.wiki/learn/blockchain/blockchain-scalability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/learn/blockchain/blockchain-scalability/</guid><description>Native Segregated Witness (Segwit) Bulletproofs Lightning Network Instant Payments Scalability Low Cost Cross-Chain Data Storage Network (DSN) Native Segregated Witness (Segwit) The Particl platform is the first blockchain in the industry to ever be deployed with a native implementation of Segwit.
This has the added benefit of making all transactions (including private ones) go through Segwit by default, resulting in better scalability and cheaper transaction fees.</description></item><item><title>Specifications</title><link>https://particl.wiki/learn/blockchain/particl-specifications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/learn/blockchain/particl-specifications/</guid><description>Blockchain Codebase Always up-to-date with latest Bitcoin Core Consensus mechanism Particl Proof-of-Stake (PPoS) Block time 120 seconds (5× faster than BTC) Block size 2 MB (2× larger than BTC) Coin supply Total &amp;amp; circulating supply 9+ million PART (check link for exact number) Community fund ~33,000 PART (owned by PART community) Staking Block reward ~0.</description></item><item><title>Transaction types</title><link>https://particl.wiki/learn/privacy/transaction-types/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/learn/privacy/transaction-types/</guid><description>As the highest privacy state requires the most transaction fee, it may not always be the best type of transaction depending on the situation, especially when privacy is not predominantly required by the user.
Particl&amp;#39;s multiple privacy states Public Blind Anon Staking Privacy ∗ ∗∗ ∗∗∗ Hidden TX amount Anon TX participants TX fees $ $$ $$$ Open Marketplace Public Blind Anon Paying for Listing fees – – Flagging items – – Purchasing items – – Funding MAD Escrow – – Why has PART different privacy states?</description></item><item><title>Accepting PART for Merchants</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/merchants/accepting-part/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/merchants/accepting-part/</guid><description>Advantages Accepting Particl (and many other cryptocurrencies) gives you – as a Seller – many advantages over traditional fiat payment systems:
No chargebacks – all cryptocurrency transactions are final, no chargebacks are possible Complete control – you are the only owner of the private keys to your wallet, no one can freeze your account or shut it down If further security and financial privacy are important to your and your business, see our Particl Open Marketplace, which was developed with exactly those in mind.</description></item><item><title>Compile &amp; Sign Particl Core builds</title><link>https://particl.wiki/dev/wallets/particl-core/compile-sign-builds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/dev/wallets/particl-core/compile-sign-builds/</guid><description>This guide will walk you through compiling your own Particl Core builds via Gitian and optionally signing the builds with your PGP key and uploading the signatures to particl/gitian.sigs repository.
The more people would compile their builds and sign them, the better.
If you can spare the time and processing power, please do! Notes Preparation Compile Check progress Post-compilation Notes This guide is focused on Ubuntu-based distros - on other distributions, you might to install more dependencies etc.</description></item><item><title>FAQ: PART coin</title><link>https://particl.wiki/support/faq/part-coin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/support/faq/part-coin/</guid><description>What is PART? Can I store PART on a hardware wallet? Where can I buy PART coins? Will PART be added to other exchanges? What is PART&amp;rsquo;s codebase? What are the transactions fees for PART? What are PART&amp;rsquo;s transactions sizes? What is PART&amp;rsquo;s inflation rate? Why has PART different privacy states? Are whitepapers available for the CT and RingCT privacy protocols? Is Segwit enabled?</description></item><item><title>Fixing syncing issues</title><link>https://particl.wiki/support/syncing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/support/syncing/</guid><description>Particl wallets are a network-based software. Make sure that no firewall or anti-virus software is blocking Particl from running or connecting the internet. If in doubt, disable them for testing purposes and enable them afterwards if you have identified your problem.
Update to latest version Make sure you&amp;rsquo;re running on latest version.
If not, update your wallet.
Reindex blockchain Relaunch the client with -reindex flag:
Windows Windows Particl Desktop: FIXME Particl Core: FIXME macOS macOS Particl Desktop: launch via /particl-desktop.</description></item><item><title>Getting started</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/getting-started/</guid><description>This series of guides will walk you through the first steps into Particl ecosystem. Buckle up!
Learn about Particl This Wiki is a great informational and supportive resource for all things Particl. Understanding the whole project might be a bit overwhelming, so we propose studing it piece by piece. Many topics are covered here, but at the bare minimum, you should read all the articles marked with ★ symbol as those are the most important ones:</description></item><item><title>Getting started with Particl Open Marketplace</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/marketplace/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/marketplace/intro/</guid><description>Requirements There are couple of things needed before you can access the Particl Open Marketplace:
Particl Desktop client installed &amp;amp; working functional (default) wallet within Particl Desktop PART coins for buying/selling (get some on available exchanges) Make sure you have a Particl Desktop installed with a working wallet before continuing.
Create Market-enabled wallet To enable the Open Marketplace, you need to create a second wallet and name it Market.</description></item><item><title>Hosting your own Coldstaking Pool</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/advanced/hosting-coldstaking-pool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/advanced/hosting-coldstaking-pool/</guid><description>For information about hosting your own coldstaking pool, visit the documentation in the particl/coldstakepool repository on GitHub:
VPS Setup Example</description></item><item><title>How to stake</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/overview/</guid><description>Staking methods Comparison Standalone staking Cold staking To learn more in-depth about Particl&amp;rsquo;s Staking feature, read Particl Staking (intro).
Staking methods You can choose from few options on how to stake:
Standalone – staking happens directly in your desktop wallet, your PC should be online ideally 24/7 (see below) Staking on a Pool – easily &amp;ldquo;pair&amp;rdquo; your desktop wallet with a Staking Pool; staking will happen automatically on pool Staking on dedicated staking device (DSD) – a fancy way to describe staking on your own SBC like Raspberry Pi or Rock64 without need to rely on third-party pool Comparison Standalone Staking pools Dedicated staking devices Difficulty to setup easiest easy moderate Staking happens directly in wallet on a pool on dedicated device Staking type &amp;ldquo;hot&amp;rdquo; staking Cold Staking Cold Staking Fees – 1–3 % – Security lower high high Howto guides – setup guide setup guide Standalone staking is easiest and fastest way to start staking.</description></item><item><title>Particl Desktop</title><link>https://particl.wiki/dev/wallets/particl-desktop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/dev/wallets/particl-desktop/</guid><description>Particl Desktop is Particl&amp;rsquo;s flagship client/wallet for interacting with PART network, including Particl Open Marketplace.
For latest development set up info
check official repo of Particl Desktop (on dev branch) Contribute
Join us in #particl-dev:matrix.org on Element (formerly Riot) for more info and/or assistance.
Keep in mind that the development currently happens on a private fork of this repo.
Requirements Node.js® v10 git yarn Installation Clone the repo &amp;amp; fetch dependencies:</description></item><item><title>Particl Desktop</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/wallets/particl-desktop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/wallets/particl-desktop/</guid><description>About Particl Desktop Features Installation Creating a new wallet Staking Recommended for beginners and majority of users Preview of Particl Desktop 3.0 About Particl Desktop While it does not currently contain all advanced features (like Particl Core), Particl Desktop is a recommended wallet for majority of users.
This wallet is intended to be the centerpiece and default wallet of the Particl platform and is heavily under development.</description></item><item><title>Particl Open Marketplace</title><link>https://particl.wiki/learn/marketplace/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/learn/marketplace/overview/</guid><description>About Open Marketplace Features Payments Listings No metadata IP address anonymization About Open Marketplace Buy and sell products and services from anyone else in the world without leaving a trail and using your favorite cryptocurrency.
The Particl Open Marketplace is a hybrid between blockchain and peer-to-peer technologies. It operates with no central authority or middleman and is exclusively owned and operated by its network of participants.</description></item><item><title>Particl with Tor</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/privacy/tor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/privacy/tor/</guid><description>a) Using the Tor Browser b) Using the Tor Daemon c) Tor as a Hidden Service The only privacy protocol that’s not enabled by default on Particl Desktop is the ability to hide your IP address using the Tor network.
While it could eventually be enabled by default or through the Settings page, Tor currently needs to be activated manually to route your Particl Desktop connection through its network.</description></item><item><title>Proposals</title><link>https://particl.wiki/learn/misc/proposals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/learn/misc/proposals/</guid><description>What can you vote on? Voting rules Non-consensus votes Consensus Votes What can you vote on? The Particl network has a tool for community members to publish proposals named the Community Crowdfunding System (CCS). Any proposal published on the CCS can be set up to require a community vote to be activated.
Read more about voting and the CCS See proposals in their discussion phase How to vote on Proposals?</description></item><item><title>RPC</title><link>https://particl.wiki/dev/api/rpc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/dev/api/rpc/</guid><description> This article hasn't been written yet, we're working on it! Want to help out? Contribute your articles!</description></item><item><title>Running multiple wallets</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/privacy/multiwallet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/privacy/multiwallet/</guid><description>Multiwallet setup Particl Desktop Particl Core Autostart multiwallet Particl Desktop Particl Core Linux You might want to create and use multiple wallets for different usage. The goal is to separate your finances, so they won&amp;rsquo;t mix up. This approach will also help you gain a bit more privacy (never linking all of your available funds).</description></item><item><title>Securely storing Recovery Phrases</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/security/recovery-phrase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/security/recovery-phrase/</guid><description>Recovery Phrases (sometimes also called Mnemonic or just Seed) are strings of usually 12, 18 or 24 words, which are used to recover crypto wallets in cases of emergency. That being said, whoever gets access to your Recovery Phrase can access your coins as well. This presents a security risk if your Recovery Phrase gets stolen or discovered by some malicious actor.
Finding the right balance Each security layer used to protect your Recovery Phrase (and optionally Recovery Passphrase) makes it harder for everyone to get access to your coins – that includes both attackers and yourself.</description></item><item><title>Wallets overview</title><link>https://particl.wiki/learn/wallets/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/learn/wallets/overview/</guid><description>You can use one or all of them, it&amp;rsquo;s up to you.
Overview Particl Desktop is a recommended wallet for most users as it offers the best of Particl&amp;rsquo;s features, including Particl Open Marketplace. Desktop Main, desktop wallets for Windows, macOS and Linux
Particl Desktop – Main, feature-rich wallet for Particl with all bells and whistles Particl Core – Qt-based wallet focused on stability and advanced features Particl Electrum – Light wallet focused on ease-of-use and accessibility Particl Copay – Mobile &amp;amp; desktop wallet with multi-sig for increased security Hardware Compatible hardware wallets for usage with Particl Core</description></item><item><title>Backup &amp; Restore wallet</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/security/backup-restore-wallet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/security/backup-restore-wallet/</guid><description>Your funds are backed up by Recovery Phrase (~ mnemonic seed) during wallet creation and that is enough to keep your coins safe. However if you want to backup all the additional data like addresses saved in Address Book and more, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to backup your wallet.dat file.
Always backup your wallet.dat to a secure place (USB, external drive etc.) – if anyone would get access to it and knew your wallet password, they could steal your coins!</description></item><item><title>Cold staking setup</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/cold-staking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/cold-staking/</guid><description>Before we dive into this guide, you might want to familiarize yourself with theory of cold staking, so that you know what we&amp;rsquo;re doing and why.
Particl&amp;rsquo;s cold staking setup is quite flexible, meaning there are many options how to stake – each approach has its pros and cons. This guide will outline all the possible variants, so that you can choose your own balance between convenience, privacy and security.</description></item><item><title>Connections &amp; peers</title><link>https://particl.wiki/support/connections/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/support/connections/</guid><description>Clear banned peers Opening Console in Particl Desktop Open Console:
Particl Desktop: click on the terminal/console icon in bottom left corner Particl Core: Help → Debug window → Console tab Enter clearbanned, press Enter and restart wallet.
Find peers from scratch Delete your peers.dat file in Particl directory. This will force the app to find new connections to peers.
Time offset error If you see a time offset error icon, it means that your machine is either ahead of behind a few seconds compared to your peers.</description></item><item><title>FAQ: Particl Open Marketplace</title><link>https://particl.wiki/support/faq/market/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/support/faq/market/</guid><description>Are there fees for using the marketplace? Who collects the fees? Do I need to keep my computer online for my listings to stay up? How long do listings stay up? Can I use any other coin other than PART? Are regular (fiat) currencies and traditional means of payment accepted? How much privacy does the marketplace offer? Is the marketplace moderated? How does the escrow system functions?</description></item><item><title>How to Buy/Sell on Open Marketplace</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/marketplace/buying-selling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/marketplace/buying-selling/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve already installed the Particl Open Marketplace and have it enabled on your Particl Desktop client, then you&amp;rsquo;re all set and ready to start buying and selling stuff for crypto without giving away your data.
Complete Buy flow Listing stage Bidding stage Order stage Escrow stage Escrow stage, pt. II Packaging &amp;amp; shipping stage Delivered/complete stage Complete Buy flow If you haven&amp;rsquo;t installed or enabled the Particl Open Marketplace yet, then follow our Getting started with Particl Open Marketplace guide!</description></item><item><title>How to choose a good password</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/security/good-passwords/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/security/good-passwords/</guid><description>Trezor wrote a very detailed and in-depth article about choosing strong passphrases for protecting recovery seeds. You can obviously follow this guide to password/passphrase-protect any kind of valuable information (like your Particl recovery seed).</description></item><item><title>MAD Escrow</title><link>https://particl.wiki/learn/marketplace/mad-escrow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/learn/marketplace/mad-escrow/</guid><description>About MAD Escrow Game Theory How does it work? Private by design Scalability About MAD Escrow Marketplaces usually have mechanisms in place to resolve disputes between buyers and vendors. This is a vital part of e-commerce because trusting strangers, especially when money is involved, has never proven to be reliable. As buyers and vendors do not know and trust each other, there has to be protection against one of the party never honoring their end of the trade.</description></item><item><title>Particl Core</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/wallets/particl-core/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/wallets/particl-core/</guid><description>Preview of Particl Core Particl Core is more lightweight than Particl Desktop, offers some advanced features like Coin Control and compatibility with hardware wallets.
However it acts like a wallet only, so you won&amp;rsquo;t have access to Particl Open Marketplace.
Download Particl Core Report bugs Features Browse &amp;amp; compare Particl Core&amp;rsquo;s features with other available wallets.
Getting started Installation Please note that even though some of these steps are optional/recommended, it is highly advised to follow all of them as it secures your funds from being lost.</description></item><item><title>Particl Electrum</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/wallets/particl-electrum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/wallets/particl-electrum/</guid><description>Preview of Particl Electrum Particl Electrum is a light wallet that doesn&amp;rsquo;t require you to download the blockchain to use. Instead, it uses the SPV technique Satoshi Nakamoto described in his Bitcoin whitepaper. This protocol lets the client verify that a transaction what successfully sent through the blockchain by only downloading the headers, which are many times smaller in size than the full blockchain.
The Particl Electrum light wallet lets you send and receive coins on desktop and Android devices and also enables a few advanced features such as multi-signatures and cold staking.</description></item><item><title>Particl Foundation</title><link>https://particl.wiki/learn/misc/particl-foundation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/learn/misc/particl-foundation/</guid><description>About Particl Foundation Purpose Funding &amp;amp; finances Initial funding Financial reports Donations Board members Address About Particl Foundation The Particl Foundation (Particl Stiftung) is a non-profit Swiss foundation registered in Zug on July 2017 with the help of Swiss law firm MME enabling the organization and deployment of funding and logistics to ensure the safe development of the Particl project and vision.</description></item><item><title>Particl Insight</title><link>https://particl.wiki/dev/api/insight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/dev/api/insight/</guid><description>This API also supports testnet data,
just replace the url with https://explorer-testnet.particl.io API Docs Block Explorer Example API calls Blockchain status Latest blocks Block info Transaction info Example API calls This is a non-exhaustive list of API example usage. See official API docs for complete list.
Blockchain status Get current blockchain data (block height, supply, difficulty(&amp;hellip;)):</description></item><item><title>Self-hosting PART payment processor</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/merchants/part-payment-processor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/merchants/part-payment-processor/</guid><description>By hosting your own instance of Particl&amp;rsquo;s BTCPayServer, you can create your very own independent payment processor for both Particl and Bitcoin.
About BTCPayServer Features Available servers Installation Requirements Generate docker-compose.yml Run BTCPayServer About BTCPayServer BTCPayServer has been ported to work on Particl by Rob (spazzymoto) by claiming a community-posted bounty on forums. Features See official BTCPayServer website for complete info about features and abilities.</description></item><item><title>About Particl's PoS</title><link>https://particl.wiki/learn/staking/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/learn/staking/intro/</guid><description>About Particl Staking Passive Income Cold Staking Cold Hardware Staking Quantum-resistance &amp;amp; Privacy About Particl Staking Proof-of-Stake (PoS) is a type of algorithm by which a cryptocurrency blockchain network aims to achieve distributed consensus. In PoS-based cryptocurrencies, the creator of the next block is chosen via various combinations of random selection of wealth and age. In contrast, the algorithm of Proof-of-Work (PoW) based cryptocurrencies such as bitcoin rewards participants who solve complicated cryptographical puzzles in order to validate transactions and create new blocks (i.</description></item><item><title>Chain forks</title><link>https://particl.wiki/support/fork/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/support/fork/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re experiencing that Particl Desktop or Particl Core wallet is not syncing any further, then it might be because you got caught on a fork due to the latest hardfork.
If you execute any transaction during this time, it will appear as if you&amp;rsquo;ve lost the coins, but don&amp;rsquo;t worry. Nothing has left your wallet.
Getting on the right chain Getting your client back to a working state requires a bit of work.</description></item><item><title>Coingecko</title><link>https://particl.wiki/dev/api/coingecko/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/dev/api/coingecko/</guid><description>Access CoinGecko data such as live pricing, trading volume, tickers, exchanges, historical data, coin info &amp;amp; images, developer &amp;amp; community stats, events, global markets, and CoinGecko Beam coins &amp;amp; exchanges status updates directly.
API v3 Docs Homepage Example API calls Get current price Coin&amp;rsquo;s current data Historic data Status updates Global cryptocurrency data More info Example API calls This is a non-exhaustive list of API example usage.</description></item><item><title>Cold Staking Pools</title><link>https://particl.wiki/learn/staking/pools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/learn/staking/pools/</guid><description>The importance of decentralization Available Staking Pools Advanced Running your own Pool In the context of cryptocurrency mining, a mining pool is the pooling of resources by miners, who share their processing power over a network, to split the reward equally, according to the amount of work they contributed to the probability of finding a block. — Wikipedia</description></item><item><title>Dedicated Staking Devices</title><link>https://particl.wiki/learn/staking/dedicated-devices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/learn/staking/dedicated-devices/</guid><description> This article hasn't been written yet, we're working on it! Want to help out? Contribute your articles!</description></item><item><title>Ledger Wallet</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/wallets/ledger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/wallets/ledger/</guid><description>Ledger Nano S About Ledger Wallet Requirements Installation Ledger Particl app Particl Core configuration Usage Sending PART using Ledger Cold staking on Ledger About Ledger Wallet Ledger Nano (S/X) is a hardware wallet which stores user&amp;rsquo;s private keys in a secure hardware device.
Hardware wallets have major advantages over standard software wallets: private keys are stored in a secure chip, and cannot be transferred out of the device.</description></item><item><title>Marketplace fees</title><link>https://particl.wiki/learn/marketplace/fees/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/learn/marketplace/fees/</guid><description>Traditional marketplaces usually have pretty complicated or extensive fee schedules. Depending on various variables such as what kind of products you sell, the number of transactions you do, your membership subscription plan, your feedback, and similar sets of data, fees can vary greatly.
The total cost associated with selling online usually includes a listing fee, a final value fee (sales fee taken on the value of the item), a subscription fee, a payment processing fee, escrow fee, and more.</description></item><item><title>Multi-signature wallets</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/security/multisig/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/security/multisig/</guid><description> This article hasn't been written yet, we're working on it! Want to help out? Contribute your articles!</description></item><item><title>Orders</title><link>https://particl.wiki/learn/marketplace/orders/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/learn/marketplace/orders/</guid><description> This article hasn't been written yet, we're working on it! Want to help out? Contribute your articles!</description></item><item><title>Particl as Tor Hidden Service</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/privacy/tor-hidden-service/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/privacy/tor-hidden-service/</guid><description>Download Particl wallet Install Tor Define HS in Tor config Find your IP for HS Modify particl.conf Start wallet It also protects your machine from geolocation and its possible ugly consequences, and automatically sets you up for both incoming and outgoing connections, helping the Particl network. It is recommended to always run the Particl through Tor.
This guide is written purely for Linux (specificaly Ubuntu-based distributions).</description></item><item><title>Particl Copay</title><link>https://particl.wiki/dev/wallets/particl-copay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/dev/wallets/particl-copay/</guid><description> This article hasn't been written yet, we're working on it! Want to help out? Contribute your articles!</description></item><item><title>Partyman staking utility</title><link>https://particl.wiki/learn/staking/partyman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/learn/staking/partyman/</guid><description>About Partyman Use cases Advantages Features About Partyman Partyman displaying staking status Partyman automates all kinds of heavy lifting related to running your own (staking) node. It&amp;rsquo;s very lightweight and runs on many platforms, including ARM (for DSD like Raspberry Pi, Rock64 and others).
As CLI, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t offer any graphical interface, but it&amp;rsquo;s still very usable and user-friendly.</description></item><item><title>Staking on DSD with Partyman</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/on-dedicated-device/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/on-dedicated-device/</guid><description>A Staking Node is a full blockchain node which has been configured to stake on behalf of your wallet (aka it has been delegated staking power over your wallet). The Staking Node is a computer running Particl that is always on and always connected to the internet. A Raspberry Pi 3 or comparable device (DSD) makes a perfect staking node as it consumes very little energy, is compact and easy to tailor for dedicated tasks.</description></item><item><title>Tips for increasing privacy</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/privacy/tips/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/privacy/tips/</guid><description>Basics Particl Transactions Balances Network Other resources Here are a few tips to keep you private as much as possible:
Basics Never brag about how much PART or BTC you own, online or offline. All it does is bringing attention to you; scammers and hackers would surely love to get a piece of your pie. It&amp;rsquo;s not worth the risk.</description></item><item><title>Chainz</title><link>https://particl.wiki/dev/api/chainz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/dev/api/chainz/</guid><description>Services provided by cryptoid.info are free of charge.
Please do not abuse them. API Docs Chainz Particl Block Explorer Example API calls Prices In BTC In USD Last 10 TXs Connected nodes PART in circulation Block count Rich list More info Example API calls Query limit!
Please limit your calls to the Query API to 1 every 10 seconds.</description></item><item><title>Coin Control</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/privacy/coin-control/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/privacy/coin-control/</guid><description> This article hasn't been written yet, we're working on it! Want to help out? Contribute your articles!</description></item><item><title>Cold staking on Ledger wallet</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/ledger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/ledger/</guid><description>This tutorial assumes Particl has been properly installed on your Ledger Nano S/X hardware device and that your Particl Core wallet is set up for Particl on Ledger.
Requirements Before starting the setup process, make sure you have:
Cold staking public key – you can get it by either: self-hosting a cold staking node (on Raspberri Pi/Rock64 etc.) or by joining one of the available staking pools A Ledger hardware wallet with Particl installed on it Ledger Live app ready to use Particl Core wallet installed and fully synced Staking setup Get your staking public key Staking Pool Via staking pool Choose one of the available staking pools and note somewhere its staking public key (they are usually right there on the top of the page).</description></item><item><title>Community governance</title><link>https://particl.wiki/learn/marketplace/governance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/learn/marketplace/governance/</guid><description>It is instead governed by its community of holders rather than a team of staff or a third-parties.
Decentralized moderation Since it is fully anonymous, it is not unlikely that undesirable items and services would be listed for sale. This is why there has to be a way to moderate the marketplace. This ensures the marketplace preserves its legitimacy and that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t become an enabler of immoral businesses and activities.</description></item><item><title>Trezor Wallet</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/wallets/trezor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/wallets/trezor/</guid><description> This article hasn't been written yet, we're working on it! Want to help out? Contribute your articles!</description></item><item><title>Trezor wallet</title><link>https://particl.wiki/dev/wallets/trezor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/dev/wallets/trezor/</guid><description>Requirements Build instructions Update bootloader Trezor One firmware Trezor T firmware Emulator support Initializing the device through trezorctl Troubleshooting Can&amp;rsquo;t find the device? What if I bricked my device somehow? Requirements Python 3.6+ (verify this by doing python3 --version) Docker (Trezor python package) Protocol Buffers (protoc) Build instructions Plug in the Trezor. Clone Particl&amp;rsquo;s Trezor firmware repository: We also need to fetch the corresponding submodules.</description></item><item><title>Verify integrity of downloads</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/security/verify-downloads/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/security/verify-downloads/</guid><description>About checksums While compiling from source is the recommended and most secure way to build the Particl platform, the team realizes this is an advanced technique that a large number of users aren&amp;rsquo;t comfortable with. For most users, each release is distributed with source code and pre-compiled distributions for Windows, Mac &amp;amp; Linux.
For Particl Core, the latest release can be found here: https://github.com/particl/particl-core/releases/latest
For Particl Desktop, the latest release can be found here: https://github.</description></item><item><title>Coinmarketcap</title><link>https://particl.wiki/dev/api/coinmarketcap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/dev/api/coinmarketcap/</guid><description> The world&amp;rsquo;s cryptocurrency data authority has a professional API made for you.
In contrast to Coingecko API, Coinmarketcap API offers limited free API access and paid premium one.
API Docs Homepage Pricing Follow official Quickstart docs on how to get started with your developer account and API access.</description></item><item><title>Cold staking on Trezor wallet</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/trezor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/trezor/</guid><description> This article hasn't been written yet, we're working on it! Want to help out? Contribute your articles!</description></item><item><title>Ledger wallet</title><link>https://particl.wiki/dev/wallets/ledger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/dev/wallets/ledger/</guid><description> This article hasn't been written yet, we're working on it! Want to help out? Contribute your articles!</description></item><item><title>Particl Copay</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/wallets/particl-copay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/wallets/particl-copay/</guid><description>About Particl Copay While it doesn&amp;rsquo;t offer all of available features (compared to other Particl wallets) it offers some unique ones.
Mainly, Particl Copay is the most accessible mobile Particl wallet and allows user-friendly multisignature wallets for increased security of your funds, or even sharing the wallet across multiple people.
Google Play App Store Download for desktop Report bugs Preview of Particl Copay app on mobile Features Browse &amp;amp; compare Particl Copay&amp;rsquo;s features with other available wallets.</description></item><item><title>Private markets</title><link>https://particl.wiki/learn/marketplace/private-bubbles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/learn/marketplace/private-bubbles/</guid><description>They are not accessible from the public interface of the Open Marketplace. The only way to access them is by entering their unique Market ID in the Particl Desktop client.
The Market ID is only known to the person that initially generated the private market and to the people he shared it with. While private markets aren&amp;rsquo;t part of the first mainnet version of the Open Marketplace, they will be implemented during the Beta phase of development.</description></item><item><title>Voting on Proposals</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/how-to-vote/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/how-to-vote/</guid><description>Voting on proposals requires you to hold Particl coins and to be actively staking on the network. If you’re voting, every block you stake within a particular voting period will register a vote.
What are Proposals and CCS?
Learn more in Learn -&amp;gt; Proposals article! How to vote To vote, first find the proposal you want to vote for on the CCS. Note down its proposal ID, the number of the block at which the voting period starts, the number of the block at which the voting period ends, and the value associated with your voting preference (i.</description></item><item><title>Currency agnosticism</title><link>https://particl.wiki/learn/marketplace/currency-agnosticism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/learn/marketplace/currency-agnosticism/</guid><description>What&amp;rsquo;s currency agnosticism? Atomic Swaps Third-Party Integrations What&amp;rsquo;s currency agnosticism? That means buyers aren&amp;rsquo;t limited to using the PART coin as a form of payment. They are able to use many currencies, including Bitcoin, among others. This provides a use-case for many different coins and gives them a fee-less and untraceable way to spend their cryptocurrencies without having to either go through a third-party or sell their coins for fiat on exchanges.</description></item><item><title>Particl CLI</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/wallets/particl-cli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/wallets/particl-cli/</guid><description>About Particl CLI Features Getting started Installation Backup &amp;amp; Restore Usage Basic commands Informative Actions Confidential Transactions (Blind) Wallet unlocking With enhanced privacy Standard unlocking Preview of Particl CLI About Particl CLI Particl-cli offers all the essential features, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t include all the advanced bells and whistles of Particl graphical clients.</description></item><item><title>Data Storage Network (DSN)</title><link>https://particl.wiki/learn/marketplace/data-storage-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/learn/marketplace/data-storage-network/</guid><description>Contrary to on-chain storage, storing data on DSN allows the platform to scale well regardless of the amount of data it uses. This form of storage works without relying on servers and without centralizing powers into masternodes.
About DSN DSN is a generic term that describes a specific set of software with the purpose of storing and retrieving data on the internet. The usage of the term DSN is simply a layer of abstraction.</description></item><item><title>Secure Messaging (SMSG)</title><link>https://particl.wiki/learn/marketplace/smsg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/learn/marketplace/smsg/</guid><description>About SMSG SMSG is a decentralized P2P message mixnet where all nodes store a copy of everyone&amp;rsquo;s end-to-end encrypted messages and data for a duration of 48 hours (which can be increased for a fee).
It is the default and most private DSN available for use on the platform.
The reference implementation is developed in C++ and incorporated into the Particl daemon. It operates parallel to Particl&amp;rsquo;s network and is hosted on the same nodes running the blockchain.</description></item><item><title>Hardware wallets</title><link>https://particl.wiki/learn/wallets/hardware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/learn/wallets/hardware/</guid><description>Advantages They have major advantages over standard software wallets: private keys are stored in a protected area of a microcontroller, and cannot be transferred out of the device in plaintext. That means your funds are safe even when connected to an infected or malicious computer or a phishing/scam web page.
Supported hardware wallets Ledger wallet Particl is currently supported by Ledger Wallet and has been integrated in such a way that it supports cold staking.</description></item><item><title>Open Market Protocol (OMP)</title><link>https://particl.wiki/learn/marketplace/open-market-protocol/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/learn/marketplace/open-market-protocol/</guid><description>Design Extensibility Privacy Portability It is a standardized and open format containing most of the economic interactions of an online marketplace. The OMP is available as an open-source protocol on Particl&amp;rsquo;s Github page and is licensed under the terms of the MIT license.
Read Open Market Protocol documentation for in-depth info. Design The Open Market Protocol is divided into two distinct formats.</description></item><item><title>Contribute to Wiki</title><link>https://particl.wiki/contribute/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/contribute/</guid><description>List of incomplete articles How to contribute Editing/creating pages Useful Shortcodes Table of Contents Buttons Images and video YouTube / Vimeo Icons Labels Hints Columns Tabs List of incomplete articles Articles tagged with &amp;ldquo;TODO&amp;rdquo; are either completely missing or just unfinished. Since other articles are linking to them, these should be written ASAP. Contributing to these is highly appreciated!</description></item></channel></rss>