<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>privacy on Particl Project Wiki</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/tags/privacy/</link><description>Recent content in privacy on Particl Project Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://geekdocs.de/tags/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Specifications</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/blockchain/particl-specifications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/blockchain/particl-specifications/</guid><description>Blockchain Codebase Always up-to-date with latest Bitcoin Core Consensus mechanism Particl Proof-of-Stake (PPoS) Block time 120 seconds (5× faster than BTC) Block size 2 MB (2× larger than BTC) Coin supply Total &amp;amp; circulating supply 9+ million PART (check link for exact number) Community fund ~33,000 PART (owned by PART community) Staking Block reward ~0.</description></item><item><title>Transaction types</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/privacy/transaction-types/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/privacy/transaction-types/</guid><description>As the highest privacy state requires the most transaction fee, it may not always be the best type of transaction depending on the situation, especially when privacy is not predominantly required by the user.
Particl&amp;#39;s multiple privacy states Public Blind Anon Staking Privacy ∗ ∗∗ ∗∗∗ Hidden TX amount Anon TX participants TX fees $ $$ $$$ Open Marketplace Public Blind Anon Paying for Listing fees – – Flagging items – – Purchasing items – – Funding MAD Escrow – – Why has PART different privacy states?</description></item><item><title>Particl with Tor</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/privacy/tor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/privacy/tor/</guid><description>a) Using the Tor Browser b) Using the Tor Daemon c) Tor as a Hidden Service The only privacy protocol that’s not enabled by default on Particl Desktop is the ability to hide your IP address using the Tor network.
While it could eventually be enabled by default or through the Settings page, Tor currently needs to be activated manually to route your Particl Desktop connection through its network.</description></item><item><title>Running multiple wallets</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/privacy/multiwallet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/privacy/multiwallet/</guid><description>Multiwallet setup Particl Desktop Particl Core Autostart multiwallet Particl Desktop Particl Core Linux You might want to create and use multiple wallets for different usage. The goal is to separate your finances, so they won&amp;rsquo;t mix up. This approach will also help you gain a bit more privacy (never linking all of your available funds).</description></item><item><title>Particl as Tor Hidden Service</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/privacy/tor-hidden-service/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/privacy/tor-hidden-service/</guid><description>Download Particl wallet Install Tor Define HS in Tor config Find your IP for HS Modify particl.conf Start wallet It also protects your machine from geolocation and its possible ugly consequences, and automatically sets you up for both incoming and outgoing connections, helping the Particl network. It is recommended to always run the Particl through Tor.
This guide is written purely for Linux (specificaly Ubuntu-based distributions).</description></item><item><title>Tips for increasing privacy</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/privacy/tips/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/privacy/tips/</guid><description>Basics Particl Transactions Balances Network Other resources Here are a few tips to keep you private as much as possible:
Basics Never brag about how much PART or BTC you own, online or offline. All it does is bringing attention to you; scammers and hackers would surely love to get a piece of your pie. It&amp;rsquo;s not worth the risk.</description></item><item><title>Coin Control</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/privacy/coin-control/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/tutorial/privacy/coin-control/</guid><description> This article hasn't been written yet, we're working on it!</description></item><item><title>Private markets</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/private-bubbles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/private-bubbles/</guid><description>They are not accessible from the public interface of the Open Marketplace. The only way to access them is by entering their unique Market ID in the Particl Desktop client.
The Market ID is only known to the person that initially generated the private market and to the people he shared it with. While private markets aren&amp;rsquo;t part of the first mainnet version of the Open Marketplace, they will be implemented during the Beta phase of development.</description></item></channel></rss>