<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Particl Desktop on Particl Project Wiki</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/tags/Particl-Desktop/</link><description>Recent content in Particl Desktop on Particl Project Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://beta.particl.wiki/tags/Particl-Desktop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting started with Particl Open Marketplace</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/marketplace/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/marketplace/intro/</guid><description>Requirements There are couple of things needed before you can access the Particl Open Marketplace:
Particl Desktop client installed &amp;amp; working functional (default) wallet within Particl Desktop PART coins for buying/selling (get some on available exchanges) Make sure you have a Particl Desktop installed with a working wallet before continuing.
Create Market-enabled wallet To enable the Open Marketplace, you need to create a second wallet and name it Market.</description></item><item><title>Particl Desktop</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/wallets/particl-desktop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/wallets/particl-desktop/</guid><description>About Particl Desktop Features Installation Creating a new wallet Staking Recommended for beginners and majority of users Preview of Particl Desktop 3.0 About Particl Desktop While it does not currently contain all advanced features (like Particl Core), Particl Desktop is a recommended wallet for majority of users.
This wallet is intended to be the centerpiece and default wallet of the Particl platform and is heavily under development.</description></item><item><title>How to Buy/Sell on Open Marketplace</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/marketplace/buying-selling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/marketplace/buying-selling/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve already installed the Particl Open Marketplace and have it enabled on your Particl Desktop client, then you&amp;rsquo;re all set and ready to start buying and selling stuff for crypto without giving away your data.
Complete Buy flow Listing stage Bidding stage Order stage Escrow stage Escrow stage, pt. II Packaging &amp;amp; shipping stage Delivered/complete stage Complete Buy flow If you haven&amp;rsquo;t installed or enabled the Particl Open Marketplace yet, then follow our Getting started with Particl Open Marketplace guide!</description></item></channel></rss>