<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>important on Particl Project Wiki</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/tags/important/</link><description>Recent content in important on Particl Project Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://beta.particl.wiki/tags/important/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Transaction types</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/privacy/transaction-types/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/privacy/transaction-types/</guid><description>As the highest privacy state requires the most transaction fee, it may not always be the best type of transaction depending on the situation, especially when privacy is not predominantly required by the user.
Particl&amp;#39;s multiple privacy states Public Blind Anon Staking Privacy ∗ ∗∗ ∗∗∗ Hidden TX amount Anon TX participants TX fees $ $$ $$$ Open Marketplace Public Blind Anon Paying for Listing fees – – Flagging items – – Purchasing items – – Funding MAD Escrow – – Why has PART different privacy states?</description></item><item><title>Particl Open Marketplace</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/marketplace/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/marketplace/overview/</guid><description>About Open Marketplace Features Payments Listings No metadata IP address anonymization About Open Marketplace Buy and sell products and services from anyone else in the world without leaving a trail and using your favorite cryptocurrency.
The Particl Open Marketplace is a hybrid between blockchain and peer-to-peer technologies. It operates with no central authority or middleman and is exclusively owned and operated by its network of participants.</description></item><item><title>Wallets overview</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/wallets/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/wallets/overview/</guid><description>You can use one or all of them, it&amp;rsquo;s up to you.
Overview Particl Desktop is a recommended wallet for most users as it offers the best of Particl&amp;rsquo;s features, including Particl Open Marketplace. Desktop Main, desktop wallets for Windows, macOS and Linux
Particl Desktop – Main, feature-rich wallet for Particl with all bells and whistles Particl Core – Qt-based wallet focused on stability and advanced features Particl Copay – Mobile &amp;amp; desktop wallet with multi-sig for increased security Hardware Compatible hardware wallets for usage with Particl Core</description></item><item><title>Backup &amp; Restore wallet</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/security/backup-restore-wallet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/security/backup-restore-wallet/</guid><description>Your funds are backed up by Recovery Phrase (~ mnemonic seed) during wallet creation and that is enough to keep your coins safe. However if you want to backup all the additional data like addresses saved in Address Book and more, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to backup your wallet.dat file.
Always backup your wallet.dat to a secure place (USB, external drive etc.) – if anyone would get access to it and knew your wallet password, they could steal your coins!</description></item><item><title>About Particl's PoS</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/staking/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/staking/intro/</guid><description>About Particl Staking Passive Income Cold Staking Cold Hardware Staking Quantum-resistance &amp;amp; Privacy About Particl Staking Proof-of-Stake (PoS) is a type of algorithm by which a cryptocurrency blockchain network aims to achieve distributed consensus. In PoS-based cryptocurrencies, the creator of the next block is chosen via various combinations of random selection of wealth and age. In contrast, the algorithm of Proof-of-Work (PoW) based cryptocurrencies such as bitcoin rewards participants who solve complicated cryptographical puzzles in order to validate transactions and create new blocks (i.</description></item></channel></rss>