<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>important on Particl Project Wiki</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/tags/important/</link><description>Recent content in important on Particl Project Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://beta.particl.wiki/tags/important/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Transaction types</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/privacy/transaction-types/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/privacy/transaction-types/</guid><description>As the highest privacy state requires the most transaction fee, it may not always be the best type of transaction depending on the situation, especially when privacy is not predominantly required by the user.
Particl&amp;#39;s multiple privacy states Public Blind Anon Staking Privacy ∗ ∗∗ ∗∗∗ Hidden TX amount Anon TX participants TX fees $ $$ $$$ Open Marketplace Public Blind Anon Paying for Listing fees – – Flagging items – – Purchasing items – – Funding MAD Escrow – – Why has PART different privacy states?</description></item><item><title>Getting started with Particl Open Marketplace</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/marketplace/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/marketplace/intro/</guid><description>Requirements There are couple of things needed before you can access the Particl Open Marketplace:
Particl Desktop client installed &amp;amp; working functional (default) wallet within Particl Desktop PART coins for buying/selling (get some on available exchanges) Make sure you have a Particl Desktop installed with a working wallet before continuing.
Create Market-enabled wallet To enable the Open Marketplace, you need to create a second wallet and name it Market.</description></item><item><title>How to stake</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/overview/</guid><description>Staking methods Comparison Standalone staking Cold staking To learn more in-depth about Particl&amp;rsquo;s Staking feature, read Particl Staking (intro).
Staking methods You can choose from few options on how to stake:
Standalone – staking happens directly in your desktop wallet, your PC should be online ideally 24/7 (see below) Staking on a Pool – easily &amp;ldquo;pair&amp;rdquo; your desktop wallet with a Staking Pool; staking will happen automatically on pool Staking on dedicated staking device (DSD) – a fancy way to describe staking on your own SBC like Raspberry Pi or Rock64 without need to rely on third-party pool Comparison Standalone Staking pools Dedicated staking devices Difficulty to setup easiest easy moderate Staking happens directly in wallet on a pool on dedicated device Staking type &amp;ldquo;hot&amp;rdquo; staking Cold Staking Cold Staking Fees – 1–3 % – Security lower high high Howto guides – setup guide setup guide Standalone staking is easiest and fastest way to start staking.</description></item><item><title>Particl Open Marketplace</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/marketplace/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/marketplace/overview/</guid><description>About Open Marketplace Features Payments Listings No metadata IP address anonymization About Open Marketplace Buy and sell products and services from anyone else in the world without leaving a trail and using your favorite cryptocurrency.
The Particl Open Marketplace is a hybrid between blockchain and peer-to-peer technologies. It operates with no central authority or middleman and is exclusively owned and operated by its network of participants.</description></item><item><title>Securely storing Recovery Phrases</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/security/recovery-phrase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/security/recovery-phrase/</guid><description>Recovery Phrases (sometimes also called Mnemonic or just Seed) are strings of usually 12, 18 or 24 words, which are used to recover crypto wallets in cases of emergency. That being said, whoever gets access to your Recovery Phrase can access your coins as well. This presents a security risk if your Recovery Phrase gets stolen or discovered by some malicious actor.
Finding the right balance Each security layer used to protect your Recovery Phrase (and optionally Recovery Passphrase) makes it harder for everyone to get access to your coins – that includes both attackers and yourself.</description></item><item><title>Wallets overview</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/wallets/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/wallets/overview/</guid><description>You can use one or all of them, it&amp;rsquo;s up to you.
Overview Particl Desktop is a recommended wallet for most users as it offers the best of Particl&amp;rsquo;s features, including Particl Open Marketplace. Desktop Main, desktop wallets for Windows, macOS and Linux
Particl Desktop – Main, feature-rich wallet for Particl with all bells and whistles Particl Core – Qt-based wallet focused on stability and advanced features Particl Copay – Mobile &amp;amp; desktop wallet with multi-sig for increased security Hardware Compatible hardware wallets for usage with Particl Core</description></item><item><title>Backup &amp; Restore wallet</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/security/backup-restore-wallet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/security/backup-restore-wallet/</guid><description>Your funds are backed up by Recovery Phrase (~ mnemonic seed) during wallet creation and that is enough to keep your coins safe. However if you want to backup all the additional data like addresses saved in Address Book and more, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to backup your wallet.dat file.
Always backup your wallet.dat to a secure place (USB, external drive etc.) – if anyone would get access to it and knew your wallet password, they could steal your coins!</description></item><item><title>Cold staking setup</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/cold-staking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/cold-staking/</guid><description>Before we dive into this guide, you might want to familiarize yourself with theory of cold staking, so that you know what we&amp;rsquo;re doing and why.
Particl&amp;rsquo;s cold staking setup is quite flexible, meaning there are many options how to stake – each approach has its pros and cons. This guide will outline all the possible variants, so that you can choose your own balance between convenience, privacy and security.</description></item><item><title>About Particl's PoS</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/staking/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/staking/intro/</guid><description>About Particl Staking Passive Income Cold Staking Cold Hardware Staking Quantum-resistance &amp;amp; Privacy About Particl Staking Proof-of-Stake (PoS) is a type of algorithm by which a cryptocurrency blockchain network aims to achieve distributed consensus. In PoS-based cryptocurrencies, the creator of the next block is chosen via various combinations of random selection of wealth and age. In contrast, the algorithm of Proof-of-Work (PoW) based cryptocurrencies such as bitcoin rewards participants who solve complicated cryptographical puzzles in order to validate transactions and create new blocks (i.</description></item></channel></rss>