<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Marketplace on Particl Project Wiki</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/</link><description>Recent content in Marketplace on Particl Project Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Particl Open Marketplace</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/overview/</guid><description>About Open Marketplace Features Payments Listings No metadata IP address anonymization About Open Marketplace Buy and sell products and services from anyone else in the world without leaving a trail and using your favorite cryptocurrency.
The Particl Open Marketplace is a hybrid between blockchain and peer-to-peer technologies. It operates with no central authority or middleman and is exclusively owned and operated by its network of participants.</description></item><item><title>MAD Escrow</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/mad-escrow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/mad-escrow/</guid><description>About MAD Escrow Game Theory How does it work? Private by design Scalability About MAD Escrow Marketplaces usually have mechanisms in place to resolve disputes between buyers and vendors. This is a vital part of e-commerce because trusting strangers, especially when money is involved, has never proven to be reliable. As buyers and vendors do not know and trust each other, there has to be protection against one of the party never honoring their end of the trade.</description></item><item><title>Marketplace fees</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/fees/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/fees/</guid><description>Traditional marketplaces usually have pretty complicated or extensive fee schedules. Depending on various variables such as what kind of products you sell, the number of transactions you do, your membership subscription plan, your feedback, and similar sets of data, fees can vary greatly.
The total cost associated with selling online usually includes a listing fee, a final value fee (sales fee taken on the value of the item), a subscription fee, a payment processing fee, escrow fee, and more.</description></item><item><title>Orders</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/orders/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/orders/</guid><description> This article hasn't been written yet, we're working on it!</description></item><item><title>Community governance</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/governance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/governance/</guid><description>It is instead governed by its community of holders rather than a team of staff or a third-parties.
Decentralized moderation Since it is fully anonymous, it is not unlikely that undesirable items and services would be listed for sale. This is why there has to be a way to moderate the marketplace. This ensures the marketplace preserves its legitimacy and that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t become an enabler of immoral businesses and activities.</description></item><item><title>Private markets</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/private-bubbles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/private-bubbles/</guid><description>They are not accessible from the public interface of the Open Marketplace. The only way to access them is by entering their unique Market ID in the Particl Desktop client.
The Market ID is only known to the person that initially generated the private market and to the people he shared it with. While private markets aren&amp;rsquo;t part of the first mainnet version of the Open Marketplace, they will be implemented during the Beta phase of development.</description></item><item><title>Currency agnosticism</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/currency-agnosticism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/currency-agnosticism/</guid><description>What&amp;rsquo;s currency agnosticism? Atomic Swaps Third-Party Integrations What&amp;rsquo;s currency agnosticism? That means buyers aren&amp;rsquo;t limited to using the PART coin as a form of payment. They are able to use many currencies, including Bitcoin, among others. This provides a use-case for many different coins and gives them a fee-less and untraceable way to spend their cryptocurrencies without having to either go through a third-party or sell their coins for fiat on exchanges.</description></item><item><title>Data Storage Network (DSN)</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/data-storage-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/data-storage-network/</guid><description>Contrary to on-chain storage, storing data on DSN allows the platform to scale well regardless of the amount of data it uses. This form of storage works without relying on servers and without centralizing powers into masternodes.
About DSN DSN is a generic term that describes a specific set of software with the purpose of storing and retrieving data on the internet. The usage of the term DSN is simply a layer of abstraction.</description></item><item><title>Secure Messaging (SMSG)</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/smsg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/smsg/</guid><description>About SMSG SMSG is a decentralized P2P message mixnet where all nodes store a copy of everyone&amp;rsquo;s end-to-end encrypted messages and data for a duration of 48 hours (which can be increased for a fee).
It is the default and most private DSN available for use on the platform.
The reference implementation is developed in C++ and incorporated into the Particl daemon. It operates parallel to Particl&amp;rsquo;s network and is hosted on the same nodes running the blockchain.</description></item><item><title>Open Market Protocol (OMP)</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/open-market-protocol/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/marketplace/open-market-protocol/</guid><description>Design Extensibility Privacy Portability It is a standardized and open format containing most of the economic interactions of an online marketplace. The OMP is available as an open-source protocol on Particl&amp;rsquo;s Github page and is licensed under the terms of the MIT license.
Read Open Market Protocol documentation for in-depth info. Design The Open Market Protocol is divided into two distinct formats.</description></item></channel></rss>