<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sellers on Particl Project Wiki</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tags/sellers/</link><description>Recent content in sellers on Particl Project Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://particl.wiki/tags/sellers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Accepting PART for Merchants</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/merchants/accepting-part/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/merchants/accepting-part/</guid><description>Advantages Accepting Particl (and many other cryptocurrencies) gives you – as a Seller – many advantages over traditional fiat payment systems:
No chargebacks – all cryptocurrency transactions are final, no chargebacks are possible Complete control – you are the only owner of the private keys to your wallet, no one can freeze your account or shut it down If further security and financial privacy are important to your and your business, see our Particl Open Marketplace, which was developed with exactly those in mind.</description></item><item><title>Self-hosting PART payment processor</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/merchants/part-payment-processor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/merchants/part-payment-processor/</guid><description>By hosting your own instance of Particl&amp;rsquo;s BTCPayServer, you can create your very own independent payment processor for both Particl and Bitcoin.
About BTCPayServer Features Available servers Installation Requirements Generate docker-compose.yml Run BTCPayServer About BTCPayServer BTCPayServer has been ported to work on Particl by Rob (spazzymoto) by claiming a community-posted bounty on forums. Features See official BTCPayServer website for complete info about features and abilities.</description></item></channel></rss>