<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blockchain on Particl Project Wiki</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/blockchain/</link><description>Recent content in Blockchain on Particl Project Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/blockchain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Latest Bitcoin codebase</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/blockchain/bitcoin-codebase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/blockchain/bitcoin-codebase/</guid><description>PART is hosted by its own blockchain and is not a token built on another chain (i.e. ERC-20 tokens).
Advantages Being built on the latest Bitcoin codebase not only allows the Particl platform to benefit from both Bitcoin’s stability and security, but also enables developers to leverage and easily fork any product, service and technology development from the Bitcoin developer community.
Recent Bitcoin developments implemented in Particl include but are not limited to:</description></item><item><title>Scalability</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/blockchain/blockchain-scalability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/blockchain/blockchain-scalability/</guid><description>Native Segregated Witness (Segwit) Bulletproofs Lightning Network Instant Payments Scalability Low Cost Cross-Chain Data Storage Network (DSN) Native Segregated Witness (Segwit) The Particl platform is the first blockchain in the industry to ever be deployed with a native implementation of Segwit.
This has the added benefit of making all transactions (including private ones) go through Segwit by default, resulting in better scalability and cheaper transaction fees.</description></item><item><title>Specifications</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/blockchain/particl-specifications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/blockchain/particl-specifications/</guid><description>Blockchain Codebase Always up-to-date with latest Bitcoin Core Consensus mechanism Particl Proof-of-Stake (PPoS) Block time 120 seconds (5× faster than BTC) Block size 2 MB (2× larger than BTC) Coin supply Total &amp;amp; circulating supply 9+ million PART (check link for exact number) Community fund ~33,000 PART (owned by PART community) Staking Block reward ~0.</description></item></channel></rss>