<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DSD on Particl Project Wiki</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/tags/DSD/</link><description>Recent content in DSD on Particl Project Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://beta.particl.wiki/tags/DSD/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cold staking setup</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/cold-staking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/cold-staking/</guid><description>Before we dive into this guide, you might want to familiarize yourself with theory of cold staking, so that you know what we&amp;rsquo;re doing and why.
Particl&amp;rsquo;s cold staking setup is quite flexible, meaning there are many options how to stake – each approach has its pros and cons. This guide will outline all the possible variants, so that you can choose your own balance between convenience, privacy and security.</description></item><item><title>Dedicated Staking Devices</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/staking/dedicated-devices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/staking/dedicated-devices/</guid><description> This article hasn't been written yet, we're working on it!</description></item><item><title>Partyman staking utility</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/staking/partyman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/learn/staking/partyman/</guid><description>About Partyman Use cases Advantages Features About Partyman Partyman displaying staking status Partyman automates all kinds of heavy lifting related to running your own (staking) node. It&amp;rsquo;s very lightweight and runs on many platforms, including ARM (for DSD like Raspberry Pi, Rock64 and others).
As CLI, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t offer any graphical interface, but it&amp;rsquo;s still very usable and user-friendly.</description></item><item><title>Staking on DSD with Partyman</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/on-dedicated-device/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/on-dedicated-device/</guid><description>A Staking Node is a full blockchain node which has been configured to stake on behalf of your wallet (aka it has been delegated staking power over your wallet). The Staking Node is a computer running Particl that is always on and always connected to the internet. A Raspberry Pi 3 or comparable device (DSD) makes a perfect staking node as it consumes very little energy, is compact and easy to tailor for dedicated tasks.</description></item></channel></rss>