<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Particl Core on Particl Project Wiki</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/tags/Particl-Core/</link><description>Recent content in Particl Core on Particl Project Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://beta.particl.wiki/tags/Particl-Core/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Compile &amp; Sign Particl Core builds</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/dev/wallets/particl-core/compile-sign-builds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/dev/wallets/particl-core/compile-sign-builds/</guid><description>This guide will walk you through compiling your own Particl Core builds via Gitian and optionally signing the builds with your PGP key and uploading the signatures to particl/gitian.sigs repository.
The more people would compile their builds and sign them, the better.
If you can spare the time and processing power, please do! Notes Preparation Compile Check progress Post-compilation Notes This guide is focused on Ubuntu-based distros - on other distributions, you might to install more dependencies etc.</description></item><item><title>Particl Core</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/dev/wallets/particl-core/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/dev/wallets/particl-core/</guid><description>Particl Core is a Qt-based wallet with advanced features focused on stability.
Compile &amp;amp; Sign Particl Core builds How to compile own Particl Core builds via Gitian and sign them with PGP</description></item><item><title>Particl Core</title><link>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/wallets/particl-core/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beta.particl.wiki/tutorial/wallets/particl-core/</guid><description>Preview of Particl Core Particl Core is more lightweight than Particl Desktop, offers some advanced features like Coin Control and compatibility with hardware wallets.
However it acts like a wallet only, so you won&amp;rsquo;t have access to Particl Open Marketplace.
Download Particl Core Report bugs Features Browse &amp;amp; compare Particl Core&amp;rsquo;s features with other available wallets.
Getting started Installation Please note that even though some of these steps are optional/recommended, it is highly advised to follow all of them as it secures your funds from being lost.</description></item></channel></rss>