<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Wallets on Particl Project Wiki</title><link>https://particl.wiki/learn/wallets/</link><description>Recent content in Wallets on Particl Project Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://particl.wiki/learn/wallets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Wallets overview</title><link>https://particl.wiki/learn/wallets/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/learn/wallets/overview/</guid><description>You can use one or all of them, it&amp;rsquo;s up to you.
Overview Particl Desktop is a recommended wallet for most users as it offers the best of Particl&amp;rsquo;s features, including Particl Open Marketplace. Desktop Main, desktop wallets for Windows, macOS and Linux
Particl Desktop – Main, feature-rich wallet for Particl with all bells and whistles Particl Core – Qt-based wallet focused on stability and advanced features Particl Electrum – Light wallet focused on ease-of-use and accessibility Particl Copay – Mobile &amp;amp; desktop wallet with multi-sig for increased security Hardware Compatible hardware wallets for usage with Particl Core</description></item><item><title>Hardware wallets</title><link>https://particl.wiki/learn/wallets/hardware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/learn/wallets/hardware/</guid><description>Advantages They have major advantages over standard software wallets: private keys are stored in a protected area of a microcontroller, and cannot be transferred out of the device in plaintext. That means your funds are safe even when connected to an infected or malicious computer or a phishing/scam web page.
Supported hardware wallets Ledger wallet Particl is currently supported by Ledger Wallet and has been integrated in such a way that it supports cold staking.</description></item></channel></rss>