<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Staking on Particl Project Wiki</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/staking/</link><description>Recent content in Staking on Particl Project Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://geekdocs.de/learn/staking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About Particl's PoS</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/staking/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/staking/intro/</guid><description>About Particl Staking Passive Income Cold Staking Cold Hardware Staking Quantum-resistance &amp;amp; Privacy About Particl Staking Proof-of-Stake (PoS) is a type of algorithm by which a cryptocurrency blockchain network aims to achieve distributed consensus. In PoS-based cryptocurrencies, the creator of the next block is chosen via various combinations of random selection of wealth and age. In contrast, the algorithm of Proof-of-Work (PoW) based cryptocurrencies such as bitcoin rewards participants who solve complicated cryptographical puzzles in order to validate transactions and create new blocks (i.</description></item><item><title>Cold Staking Pools</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/staking/pools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/staking/pools/</guid><description>The importance of decentralization Available Staking Pools Advanced Running your own Pool In the context of cryptocurrency mining, a mining pool is the pooling of resources by miners, who share their processing power over a network, to split the reward equally, according to the amount of work they contributed to the probability of finding a block. — Wikipedia</description></item><item><title>Dedicated Staking Devices</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/staking/dedicated-devices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/staking/dedicated-devices/</guid><description> This article hasn't been written yet, we're working on it!</description></item><item><title>Partyman staking utility</title><link>https://geekdocs.de/learn/staking/partyman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekdocs.de/learn/staking/partyman/</guid><description>About Partyman Use cases Advantages Features About Partyman Partyman displaying staking status Partyman automates all kinds of heavy lifting related to running your own (staking) node. It&amp;rsquo;s very lightweight and runs on many platforms, including ARM (for DSD like Raspberry Pi, Rock64 and others).
As CLI, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t offer any graphical interface, but it&amp;rsquo;s still very usable and user-friendly.</description></item></channel></rss>