<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ledger wallet on Particl Project Wiki</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tags/Ledger-wallet/</link><description>Recent content in Ledger wallet on Particl Project Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://particl.wiki/tags/Ledger-wallet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ledger Wallet</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/wallets/ledger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/wallets/ledger/</guid><description>Ledger Nano S About Ledger Wallet Requirements Installation Ledger Particl app Particl Core configuration Usage Sending PART using Ledger Cold staking on Ledger About Ledger Wallet Ledger Nano (S/X) is a hardware wallet which stores user&amp;rsquo;s private keys in a secure hardware device.
Hardware wallets have major advantages over standard software wallets: private keys are stored in a secure chip, and cannot be transferred out of the device.</description></item><item><title>Cold staking on Ledger wallet</title><link>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/ledger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/tutorial/staking/ledger/</guid><description>This tutorial assumes Particl has been properly installed on your Ledger Nano S/X hardware device and that your Particl Core wallet is set up for Particl on Ledger.
Requirements Before starting the setup process, make sure you have:
Cold staking public key – you can get it by either: self-hosting a cold staking node (on Raspberri Pi/Rock64 etc.) or by joining one of the available staking pools A Ledger hardware wallet with Particl installed on it Ledger Live app ready to use Particl Core wallet installed and fully synced Staking setup Get your staking public key Staking Pool Via staking pool Choose one of the available staking pools and note somewhere its staking public key (they are usually right there on the top of the page).</description></item><item><title>Ledger wallet</title><link>https://particl.wiki/dev/wallets/ledger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/dev/wallets/ledger/</guid><description> This article hasn't been written yet, we're working on it! Want to help out? Contribute your articles!</description></item><item><title>Hardware wallets</title><link>https://particl.wiki/learn/wallets/hardware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://particl.wiki/learn/wallets/hardware/</guid><description>Advantages They have major advantages over standard software wallets: private keys are stored in a protected area of a microcontroller, and cannot be transferred out of the device in plaintext. That means your funds are safe even when connected to an infected or malicious computer or a phishing/scam web page.
Supported hardware wallets Ledger wallet Particl is currently supported by Ledger Wallet and has been integrated in such a way that it supports cold staking.</description></item></channel></rss>